Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music Records, 1996-2011
State University of New York at Buffalo, Music Library
- 2011, XV.; Item 2011-001-2011-195
  - Audio and video recordings, 2011, C.; Item 2011-039-2011-153
    - Smith, Simon, 1983- (Box 90, Item 2011-099)
    - Swayne, Adam (Box 90, Item 2011-100)
    - Swayne, Adam (Box 90, Item 2011-101)
    - Tedeschi, Simon, 1981- (Box 90, Item 2011-102)
    - Theodorakis, Ermis (Box 90, Item 2011-103)
    - Theodorakis, Ermis (Box 90, Item 2011-104)
    - Torquati, Emanuele, 1978- (Box 90, Item 2011-105)
    - Venturini, Franco (Box 90, Item 2011-106)
    - Venturini, Franco (Box 90, Item 2011-107)
    - Venturini, Franco (Box 90, Item 2011-108)
    - Yang, Jing (Box 90, Item 2011-109)
    - Yang, Jing (Box 90, Item 2011-110)
    - Yip, Michelle (Box 90, Item 2011-111)
    - Yip, Michelle (Box 90, Item 2011-112)
    - Yip, Michelle (Box 90, Item 2011-113)
    - Yip, Michelle (Box 90, Item 2011-114)
    - Adams, Samuel (Box 91, Item 2011-115)
    - Akiho, Andy (Box 91, Item 2011-116)
    - Blasco, Scott, 1978- (Box 91, Item 2011-117)
    - Broberg, Kirsten (Box 91, Item 2011-118)
    - Carter, Ryan, 1980- (Box 91, Item 2011-119)
    - Cerrone, Christopher (Box 91, Item 2011-120)
    - Chen, Hsin-lei (Box 91, Item 2011-121)
    - Chen, Hsin-lei (Box 91, Item 2011-122)
    - Ciupinski, Jakub (Box 91, Item 2011-123)
    - Dicke, Ian, 1982- (Box 91, Item 2011-124)
    - Dietz, Christopher, 1977- (Box 91, Item 2011-125)
    - Emfietzis, Gregory (Box 91, Item 2011-126)
    - Evanoff, Ray (Box 91, Item 2011-127)
    - Galindo, Gilbert (Box 91, Item 2011-128)
    - Goddard, Christopher (Box 91, Item 2011-129)
    - Holloway-Nahum, Aaron (Box 91, Item 2011-130)
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie Tsang (Box 91, Item 2011-131)
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie Tsang (Box 91, Item 2011-132)
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie Tsang (Box 91, Item 2011-133)
    - Iturralde, Carlos (Box 91, Item 2011-134)
    - Ivanova, Vera (Box 91, Item 2011-135)
    - Kolm, Jonathan (Box 91, Item 2011-136)
    - Lee, Wendy Wan-Ki (Box 91, Item 2011-137)
    - Maloy, Kristopher (Box 91, Item 2011-138)
    - Mark, Brian (Box 91, Item 2011-139)
    - Moya, Reinaldo (Box 91, Item 2011-140)
    - Neustadter, Garth (Box 91, Item 2011-141)
    - Noble, Andrew R. (Box 91, Item 2011-142)
    - Oakley (Oaklei), George (Box 91, Item 2011-143)
    - Sarto, Andrea (Box 91, Item 2011-144)
    - Schankler, Isaac (Box 91, Item 2011-145)
    - Seglias, Zesses (Box 91, Item 2011-146)
    - Seo, Ju Ri (Box 91, Item 2011-147)
    - Smith, Neil Thomas (Box 91, Item 2011-148)
    - Tzortzis, Nicolas (Box 91, Item 2011-149)
    - VanHassel, Dan (Box 91, Item 2011-150)
    - Wang, Ashley Fu-Tsun (Box 91, Item 2011-151)
    - Williams, Natalie (Box 91, Item 2011-152)
    - Wohl, Daniel (Box 91, Item 2011-153)
  - Scores, 2011, D.; Item 2011-154-2011-195
    - Adams, Samuel Piano step, 2010, 16 p. of music; 26 x 34 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-154)
    - Akiho, Andy Vick(y/i), 2008, 10 p. of music; 28 x 44 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-155)
    - Blasco, Scott, 1978- Queen of heaven, 2010, 1 score (18 p.); 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-156)
    - Broberg, Kirsten Constellations, 2008, 14 p. of music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-157)
    - Carter, Ryan, 1980- 20 (or so) variations for clarinet, cello, piano, and electronics, 2009, 1 score (40 p.); 31 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-158)
      For clarinet, violoncello, piano, and electronics.
    - Cerrone, Christopher Hoyt-Schermerhorn, 2010, 1 score (3 p.); 28 x 44 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-159)
      For solo amplified piano and live electronics.
    - Chen, Hsin-Lei Ding Feng Bo, 2010, 1 score (20 p.); 30 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-160)
    - Chen, Hsin-Lei Five pieces for piano, 2002, 10 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-161)
    - Chen, Hsin-Lei Renascence, 2010, 1 score (49 p.); 30 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-162)
    - Ciupinski, Jakub Morning tale, undated, 14 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-163)
    - Dicke, Ian, 1982- Déjà, 2009, 1 score (45 p.); 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-164)
    - Dicke, Ian, 1982- White parasol, 2008, 16 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-165)
    - Dietz, Christopher, 1977- Five reflections of the Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, 2009, 30 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-166)
    - Emfietzis, Gregory DIY 1: the pianist & the lamp, undated, 1 score (4 p.); 21 x 30 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-167)
      For a pianist and a lamp.
    - Evanoff, Ray Diagrams of drawings not meant to correspond, 2009, 6 p. of music; 30 x 42 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-168)
    - Galindo, Gilbert Veiled reverie, 2006, 13 p. of music; 22 x 36 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-169)
    - Goddard, Christopher 4 concert études, 2010, 5, 3, 7, 9 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-170)
    - Holloway-Nahum, Aaron Cinq merveilles, 2010, 1 score (11 p.); 30 cm. (Box 92, Item 2011-171)
      For solo piano and percussion.
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie-Tsang Autumn steps, undated, 12 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-172)
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie-Tsang Autumn's rain, 2008, 1 score (16 p.); 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-173)
      For clarinet, vibraphone, violin, and violoncello.
    - Isaiah, Lee Chie-Tsang Autumn's heart. Maple. Fragrance, 2009, 1 score (10 p.); 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-174)
    - Iturralde, Carlos Cupid's deeds, 2005, 1 score (37 p.); 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-175)
      For piano, strings, woodwinds, and percussion.
    - Ivanova, Vera Aftertouch, 2005-2006, 11 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-176)
    - Kolm, Jonathan A dream within a dream, 2004, 1 score (10 p.); 38 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-177)
      For soprano, violoncello, and piano.
    - Lee, Wendy Wan-Ki Kirie, 2008, 8 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-178)
    - Mark, Brian Sliding doors, 2007, 14 p. of music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-179)
    - Moya, Reinaldo Short suite for piano, 2006, 7 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-180)
    - Neustadter, Garth Untangoed, 2010, 13 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-181)
    - Noble, Andrew R. The party line, 2005-2006, 42 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-182)
    - Oakley (Oklei), George Sonata-Fantasia, 2010, 46 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-183)
    - Sarto, Andrea Kalkós, 2006, 1 score (38 p.); 42 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-184)
    - Schankler, Isaac Man on wiire, 2010, 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-185)
      For piano, Wii remote, and electronics.
    - Seglias, Zesses Sei strumenti in cerca del compositore, 2010, 1 score (42 p.); 21 x 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-186)
      For flute, clarinet, piano, violin, viola, and violoncello.
    - Seo, Ju Ri ( ), 2009, 13 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-187)
    - Smith, Neil Thomas The amazing and true adventures: 5 vignettes from Cervantes's Don Quixote, undated, 1 score (12 p.); 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-188)
    - Solitro, Tony Hindsight, 2009, 1 score (15 p.); 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-189)
      For flute, clarinet, violoncello, and piano.
    - Tzortzis, Nicolas L'assemblage du menteur, 2010, 6 p. of music; 21 x 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-190)
    - VanHassel, Dan Lush intrinsic, 2009, 18 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-191)
      For piano and live electronics.
    - Wang, Ashley Fu-Tsun Intimate rejection, 2008, 6 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-192)
    - Wang, Ashley Fu-Tsun Retrogradable dilution, 2009, 1 score (14 p.); 28 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-193)
    - Williams, Natalie Five bagatelles, 2010, 8 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-194)
    - Wohl, Daniel Aorta, 2010, 19 p. of music; 30 cm. (Box 93, Item 2011-195)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Williams, Jan, 1939-
Subjects
Music--Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music--Archives
Genres
Administrative records; Sound recordings
Associated Material
Separated Material
Tax forms and college transcripts have been destroyed.
Commercial sound recordings
Commercially produced recordings are removed from the collection. Those that are duplicates to the general collection are withdrawn; those that are new to the general collection are added to that collection.
Commercially produced recordings removed to the general collection
Albany Symphony Orchestra. Brutal Reality: TROY 354, Albany Records, 1999
Albany Symphony Orchestra. Lopatnikoff, Helps, Thomson and Kurka: TROY 591, Albany Records, 2003
American Composers Forum. Sonic Circuits Vi: 115, Innova, 1998
Americas Vocal Ensemble. Serenata: N/S R 1024, North/South Recordings, 2001
Andrew Imbrie. Spring Fever, Chicago Bells, Songs of Then and Now: TROY538, Albany Records, 2002
Barton Workshop. Works for Trombone: KTC 1227, Etcetera, 2000
Blazewicz, Marcin. Selections: KOS CD06, Kos Records, 1993
Burton Beerman, Bicinia Duo, Stanley Yerlow, Shiau-uen Ding. Beerman Unplugged, Almost: CPS-8757, Capstone Records, 2006
Carter Pann. American Classics: Naxos 8.559043, Naxos, 2000
Cassatt String Quartet. Cassatt: CD 67, Composer's Recordings, Inc, 1994
Common Sense Composers' Collective and American Baroque. The Shock of the Old: CD000513, Santa Fe Music Group, 2001
Concours Molinari. 2001-2002: ACD 2 2286, ATMA Classique, 2003
David Tannenbaum. The Book of Abbeyozzuo - Terry Riley: NA 106 CD, New Albion Records, 1999
Debussy Trio. In the Shadow of a Miracle: SXCD5005, Sierra records, 1996
Deep Listening Band. Tosca Salad: DL 3 1995 CD, Deep Listening, 1995
Empyrean Ensemble. Music of Ross Bauer, Andrew Frank, Pablo Ortiz: CRC 2386, Centaur, 1998
Ensemble Aleph. Arrets Frequents: 9813, Vand'Oeuvre, 1997
Ensemble Opus Posth. Come In!: CCn'C 01412, CCn'C Records, 2001
The Esoterics. Elementia: CD-0301, Terpsichore Records, 2001
Frederik Croene. Frederik Croene, piano: HA 6003 2, HA' Records, 2003
George Koumentakis, Michalis Lapidakis, Markos Moisides. Journey into the Night, In a State of Flux IIa, Toru's Dream
The Gregg Smith Singers. Like Shining: Volume 6, Living Artist Recordings, 2000
Hannes Seidl. Musik fur ubers sofa: WER 6574 2, Wergo, 2009
Harold Schiffman. Symphony and Concerti: N/S R 1021, North/South Recordings, 1999
Horacio Lavandera. Compositores Espanoles de la Generacion del 51: VRS 2057, Verso, 2007
Jessica Pavone. Quotidian: Peacock 08, Peacock Recordings
Karen DeWig. Figures in a Landscape: CRC 2467, Centaur, 2000
Kaila Fexer and Third Ear. Listen: 742262; Compass Records, 1995
Larry Bell. River of Ponds: N/S R 1018, North/South Recordings, 1998
Mark Pekarsky Percussion Ensemble. The True Story of Noise Music: B084, Mark Pekarsky, 1999
Matthew Welch. Ceol Nua: CD LR 336, Leo Records, 2002
Matthew Welch. Hag at the Churn: Newsonic 33, Newsonic records, 2003
Max Lifchitz. Diversions: N/S R 1026, North/South Recordings, 2002
The Meadows Percussion Ensemble. Strike: The Music of Motion: GSCD-346, Gasparo Records, 2000
New Century Saxophone Quartet. Home Grown: CCS 15498, Channel Classics, 1999
North/South Consonance Ensemble. Silhouettes: Vocal and Instrumental American Music: N/S R 1013, North/South Recordings, 1997
Parnassus. Stefan Wolpe: 3-7141-2 H1, KOCH International Classics, 1992
Quatuor Molinari. R. Murray Schafer String Quartets 1-7: ACD 2 2188/89, ATMA Classique, 2000
Richard Toensing. Responsoria: N/S R 1022, North/South Recordings, 2000
Rova. The Works (volume 1): 120176-2, Soul-Note, 1995
Various Artists. 541 Volume 1: innova 635, American Composers Forum, 2005
Wolpe, Feldman, Zimmerman, Seel. Four Generations: hat[hut]Art 139, Hat Hut records, Ltd., 2001
Commercially produced recordings removed from the collection (and already in the general library collection)
Annie Gosfield. Flying Sparks and Heavy Machinery: TZ 7069, TZADIK, 2001
Bang on a Can. Renegade Heaven: CA21001, Cantaloupe, 2000
Common Sense Composers' Collective. Common Sense: CD 731, Composers Recordings, Inc., 1997
Common Sense Composers' Collective and American Baroque. The Shock of the Old: CD000513, Santa Fe Music Group, 2001 (Two Copies)
CORE Ensemble. Donald Martino: A Jazz Set: 80518-2, New World Records, 1996
Cygnus Ensemble. Broken Consort: CD 834, Composers Recordings, Inc., 2000
Da Capo Chamber Players Music by Shulamit Ran: BCD 9052: Bridge Records, 1995
Easley Blackwood. Microtonal: CDR 90000 018, Cedille Records, 1994
Eighth Blackbird. Thirteen Ways: CDR 90000 067, Cedille Records, 2003
Elodie Lauten. The Deux Ex Machina Cycle: CD 4013, 4Tay Inc., 1999
The Esoterics. Elementia: CD-0301, Terpsichore Records, 2001
Frank Ferko. Stabat Mater: CDR 90000 051, Cedille Records, 2000
Jenny Q Chai. New York love songs: CD 003, ArpaViva, 2010
London Sinfonietta. Live from State of the Nation 2001: NMC D078, NMC Recordings, 2002
Meredith Monk. Mercy: ECM New Series 1829 289 472 468-2, ECM Records, 2002
Meridian Arts Ensemble. Five: CCS 9496, Channel Classics, 1995
Meridian Arts Ensemble. Prime Meridian: CCS 8195, Channel Classics, 1995
New Century Saxophone Quartet. Home Grown: CCS 15498, Channel Classics, 1999
New Millennium Ensemble. Morton Feldman: 3-7466-2 HI, KOCH International Classics, 2000
The New York New Music Ensemble. New Electro-Acoustic Music: CRC 2338, CENTAUR, 1998
The New York Virtuoso Singers. Charles Wuorinen: Genesis Mass: 3-7336-2H1, Koch International Classics, 1995
The New York Virtuosi Singers. To Orpheus: CD 615, Composers Recordings, Inc., 1992
North/South Consonance Ensemble. ... In the Receding Mist...: N/S R 1003, North/South Recordings, 1994
Phyllis Chen. Uncaged Toy Piano.: CAG 104, Concert Artists Guild, 2009
Riverside Symphony. Andrew Imbrie: Requiem, Piano Concerto No. 3: BRIDGE 9091, Bridge Records, 1999
Riverside Symphony. Mario Davidovsky, Anthony Korf, Maurice Wright: NW 383-2, New World Records, 1990
Sequitur. Concertos: TROY 607, Albany Records, 2003
Society of Composers, Inc. Milestones: CPS-8701, Capstone Records, 2002
Steve Reich. Triple Quartet: 79546-2, Nonesuch Records, 2001
Various Artists. Contemporary Music from Ireland, Volume 7: CMC CD07, Contemporary Music Centre, 2008
The Warsaw Philharmonic and Choir. George Crumb 70th Birthday Album: Bridge 9095, Bridge Records, 1999
Zeitgeist. If Tigers Were Clouds...: innova 589, American Composers Forum, 2003
Scores
Scores included in applications are added to the general collection. Those that are duplicates to the general collection are withdrawn.
Adashi, Judah The Dark Hours (for bassoon and piano)
Balter, Marcos RE: (no subject) (for violin and piano)
Berkowitz, Aaron Tony said he saw birds flying (for solo piano)
Black, Annesley LAUF (for nine musicians)
Brackel, Christopher Meta-Tango (Solo Piano)
Broberg, Kirsten Emergence
Cavallone, Paolo Confii (per pianoforte)
Cerrone, Christopher Averno: a fragment
Chabashvili, Eka Seven Wonders of World (7 novellas for Chamber Composition): The Colossus of Rhodes
da Silva, Patricio Three Movements for Solo Piano
Di Castri, Zosha The Thinking Eye (for solo piano)
Francis, Ryan Consolations (for piano solo)
Freeman, Jason Piano Etudes
Freeman, Jason Sonata (for solo piano)
Gorton, David Ondine (for solo piano)
Grossman, Jorge Sialia (for clarinet in B-flat, violoncello and piano)
Haber, Yotam Three Piano Pieces: etude 3, slip, etude 5
Hallman, Joseph Cancione
Hallman, Joseph Danza (for solo Harp)
Hallman, Joseph Handfuls: 11 songs after poems by Carl Sandburg
Hallman, Joseph Sonata for Violin and Piano
Hochman, Gilad Quest (for saxophone and piano)
Hochman, Gilad Slightly Disturbed (Monodrama for Violin, Clarinet and Cello)
Holland, Jonathan Bailey Songs of Experience (voice and piano)
Hollington, Barnaby Mechanical Avunculogratulation (ou L'Art de Fabriquer des Machines a Saluer les Oncles)
Holt, James Pieces for Piano (for Solo Piano)
Huang, Tsai-Yun Blazing Dawn (for piano solo)
Huang, Tsai-Yun Full and Empty (for string quartet)
Huang, Tsai-Yun Imaginary Place (for piano and 2-channel tape)
Imai, Shintaro Figure in Movement II (for piano and real-time audio/visual processing technique)
Ippolito, Michael Blackbird Variations (for solo piano)
Jacoby, Derek In Memoriam: EV1 (for solo piano)
Jie, Wang Game for Two
Johnson, Derek Balance (for violin, viola, cello & piano)
Kellogg, Daniel scarlet thread
King, Mary Shadow Builders (for piano)
Klingbeil, Michael Monoliths and Interludes (for piano solo)
Kojs, Juraj All Forgotten
Krashenko, Olga From...
Lang, David after gravity (piano four hands)
Latham, Clara Luftkussen (for piano solo)
Lee, Damon Faim (pour Piano et Sopran)
Liddell, Patrick Jessica's Theme Song
Maloy, Kristopher Quartet in Four Actions (for clarinet, violin, cello and piano)
Mason, Christian Equinoxes of the Infinite
McCormack, Timothy ]regate[ s.p. ]Aggre[
Miller, Pierre (pseudonym A. Nicky Scribs) Three Concert Studies (for solo piano)
Minikakis, Stratis Distillations of the Night (for clarinet in B flat, violin, viola, cello and piano)
Moore, Christopher Tentacles and Knot Formations
Muhly, Nico A Hudson Cycle
Nagy, Zvonimir ... of the lake
Osborne, Thomas And the Waves Sing Because They are Moving (for solo piano)
Plylar, David The Artist's Studio
Power, Karen like piglets at a market (for solo piano)
Power, Karen Old Fashioned Chocolate Fondue Fountain
Prangcharoen, Narong Three Minds (for Solo Piano)
Prins, Stefan Memory Space #2 (for solo recorder, electric guitar, piano, percussion, double bass and live-electronics)
Quintana, Josep l/b
Roberto, Rusconi Isole nella Corrente
Russell, Jonathan Metamorphosis #1 (for piano solo)
Schuessler, Philip Roadside Picnic (for two pianos)
Sivan, Noam Five Miniatures for Clarinet in B flat and Piano
Sivan, Noam Three Preludes
Smetryns, Thomas About Morse and Mutual Understanding
Stout, Alastair Cave Paintings
Stumpff, Nathan J. Road Trip Songs, Vol. 1, No. 3: Volkswagen Hobo
Tzortzis, Nicolas Desaxe (pour dix musiciens)
Tzortzis, Nicolas L'accordage du menteur (pour piano seul)
Tzortzis, Nicolas Mnesique (pour cinq musiciens)
VanHassel, Dan Explosive Spontaneous (for piano)
Verlingieri, Gianluca labirinti della memoria (four pieces for piano solo)
Wah-Hei, Ng 3 bagatelles for piano
Warshaw, Dalit Dance of the Red Dreidl: theme and variations on a Hebrew Chanukah tune for solo piano
Watkins, Zachary (206)culture
Williams, Natalie Entropy (for piano solo)
Wolek, Krzysztof Mor Madmen only! (for tenor saxophone and piano)
Yen, Ming-Hsiu Two Old Postcards from Formosa (for piano)
Yun, Du Vicissitudes No. 1
Yun, Du Vicissitudes No. 3
Zamboni, Mauricio F H Crazy
Zamboni, Mauricio Five Orchestral Moments
Zamboni, Mauricio Periclitancia (for two Marimbas)
Zhou, Xu A Montage Lullaby ----- for piano
Zhou, Xu Fluctuation (for soprano, flute, clarinet (B flat), violin, violoncello, piano and percussion)
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Archive
Mus. Arc. 1
The Yvar Mikhashoff Archive consists of several components, including compositions, transcriptions, commissioned tangos, annotated scores, recordings, photographs, and slides.